<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml>
    
  <category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <template>Do you want to:
        <button>
            <text>Test my Skin Type</text>
            <postback>SkinType</postback>
        </button>
        <button>
            <text>Improve my Skincare Routine</text>
            <postback>Routine</postback>
        </button>
        <button>
            <text>Ask a specific question</text>
            <postback>Question</postback>
        </button>
    </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Hi</pattern>
      <template>
          <random>
              <li>Hi, there. </li>
              <li>Hello! </li>
              <li>It’s good to see you. </li>
              <li>It’s nice to meet you. </li>
          </random>
        My name is SkinCare Chatbot and I'm here to help you improve your skincare.
        Bear in mind that I don't offer medical advice and if you have severe issues you should visit a professional.
        <split/>
        Do you want to:
        <button>
            <text>Test my Skin Type</text>
            <postback>SkinType</postback>
        </button>
        <button>
            <text>Improve my Skincare Routine</text>
            <postback>Routine</postback>
        </button>
        <button>
            <text>Ask a specific question</text>
            <postback>Question</postback>
        </button>
      </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Hello</pattern>
      <template><srai>Hi</srai></template>
  </category>
  
  
  <category>
      <pattern>SkinType</pattern>
      <template>Which most closely describes the look of your pores?
      
      <button>
          <text>A. Large and visible all over. </text>
          <postback>Q1</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>B. Medium-sized all over. </text>
          <postback>Q1</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>C. Larger or medium and only visible in the T-zone.</text>
          <postback>Q1</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>D. Small, not easily noticed all over.</text>
          <postback>Q1</postback>
      </button>
      </template>
  </category> 
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Q1</pattern>
      <template>When does your skin look red?
      <button>
          <text>A. Anytime I have blemishes</text>
          <postback>Q2</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>B. Whenever and wherever I use new products.</text>
          <postback>Q2</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>C. Sometimes, but only around my cheeks.</text>
          <postback>Q2</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>D. More often than I care to admit. </text>
          <postback>Q2</postback>
      </button>
      </template>
  </category>
  
 <category>
     <pattern>Q2</pattern>
     <template>I would describe the shine of my skin like this:
     <button>
         <text>A. Bright like a diamond.</text>
         <postback>Q3</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>B. I get more stinging than shine.</text>
         <postback>Q3</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>C. Shiny in my T-zone, but dull on my cheeks.</text>
         <postback>Q3</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>D. Dull everywhere.</text>
         <postback>Q3</postback>
     </button>
     </template>
 </category>
 
 <category>
     <pattern>Q3</pattern>
     <template>How does it feel when you touch your skin?
     <button>
         <text>A.Slick and greasy.</text>
         <postback>Q4</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>B. Irritated and angry.</text>
         <postback>Q4</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>C.Oily in places and dry in others.</text>
         <postback>Q4</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>D.Rough and scaly.</text>
         <postback>Q4</postback>
     </button>
     </template>
 </category>
 
 <category>
     <pattern>Q4</pattern>
     <template>In the afternoon, my skin needs:
     <button>
         <text>A.Blotting or powder all over?</text>
         <postback>Q5</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>B.A refreshing spritz of facial spray.</text>
         <postback>Q5</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>C.Blotting or powdering on the forehead, nose, and/or chin.</text>
         <postback>Q5</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>D.Moisturizing, moisturizing, moisturizing.</text>
         <postback>Q5</postback>
     </button>
     </template>
 </category>
 
 <category>
     <pattern>Q5</pattern>
     <template>How does your skin feel after you wash your face?
     <button>
         <text>A. Clean, for now, but the oil is coming soon.</text>
         <postback>Q6</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>B.Itchy and a little bit dry.</text>
         <postback>Q6</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>C. Clean and great in my T-zone, but my cheeks are a little bit dried out.</text>
         <postback>Q6</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>D.Stripped of moisture.</text>
         <postback>Q6</postback>
     </button>
     </template>
 </category>
 
 <category>
     <pattern>Q6</pattern>
     <template>Pick the one that best describes your skin's relationship with pimples and blackheads.
     <button>
         <text>A. I hate them, but they love me. </text>
         <postback>RESULTS</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>B.My blemishes are more likely to be broken capillaries or rashes.</text>
         <postback>RESULTS</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>C.They have their territory around my T-zone, and I have claimed the cheeks for my own.</text>
         <postback>RESULTS</postback>
     </button>
     <button>
         <text>D.I'd trade my skin's flakiness and tightness for a few blackheads. </text>
         <postback>RESULTS</postback>
     </button>
     </template>
 </category>
 
 <category>
     <pattern>RESULTS</pattern>
     <template>If  most of your answers were A, your skin type is Oily.<break/>
     If B, your skin type is Sensitive. <break/>
     C means you have Combination skin type. <break/>
     D stands for Dry skin type. <break/>
     If your answers didn't reveal your skin type, try visitting a dermatologist.</template>
 </category>
  
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Routine</pattern>
      <template>i need your skin type if you dont know make your test
      <button>
          <text>Oily</text>
          <postback>Oily</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>Sensitive</text>
          <postback>Sensitive</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>Combination</text>
          <postback>Combination</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
          <text>Dry</text>
          <postback>Dry</postback>
      </button>
      </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Oily</pattern>
      <template>
          First of all, you need to know the corect order of skin care - it really matters.
          <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.dermstore.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/order-of-skin-care-products-1.jpg</image>
    <delay>10</delay>
     The skincare routine for oily skin includes ingredients that help control excess oil production. 
     <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.byrdie.com/thmb/zSpNehFxmk2lKi9-sGnlIIB88TM=/800x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc():format(webp)/oily-skin-add34874da4e4c7795d55a8313a0ca64.png</image> 
    </template>
  </category>
 
  <category>
      <pattern>Sensitive</pattern>
      <template>First of all, you need to know the corect order of skin care - it really matters.
      <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.dermstore.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/order-of-skin-care-products-1.jpg</image>
     <delay>10</delay>
     The skincare routine for sensitive skin needs to be non-irritating. People often think of sensitive skin as acne-prone, but it is more accurate to consider it as skin that gets red and irritated easily.
     <delay>5</delay>
     <image>https://www.byrdie.com/thmb/W5-x3R7Gw8wIVPn6toD8kqgJW-Y=/800x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc():format(webp)/sensitive-skin-2f4d5a41203a4215a3a94bf700029d33.png</image>
   </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Combination</pattern>
      <template>First of all, you need to know the corect order of skin care - it really matters.
       <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.dermstore.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/order-of-skin-care-products-1.jpg</image>
    <delay>10</delay>
    The skincare routine for combination skin includes ingredients that treat a wide range of skin concerns. 
    <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.byrdie.com/thmb/9-30jt2GIR6A0xdBcTMqR9Yywjg=/800x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc():format(webp)/combination-skin-e3efac61c03c45a58bc167e27891dc17.png</image>
    </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Dry</pattern>
      <template>First of all, you need to know the corect order of skin care - it really matters.
      <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.dermstore.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/order-of-skin-care-products-1.jpg</image>
    <delay>10</delay>
    The best skincare routine for dry skin typically includes products that keep the skin hydrated. Look for serums containing vitamins E, A, and C.
    <delay>5</delay>
    <image>https://www.byrdie.com/thmb/FWI4jSeY5dzYv2fg2iXbZTD2WuU=/800x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc():format(webp)/dry-skin-9b5f43c5569f4fe1a890b80cf497a9a8.png</image>
    </template>
  </category>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>Question</pattern>
      <template>What can I help you with?</template>
  </category>
  
  
  <category>
      <pattern> ^ Acne ^</pattern>
      <template>Acne develops when sebum — an oily substance that lubricates your hair and skin — and dead skin cells plug hair follicles.
      Bacteria can trigger inflammation and infection resulting in more severe acne - if you experience that, please visit a doctor.
      <button>
          <text>More information about Acne you can find here</text>
          <url>https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/acne/symptoms-causes/syc-20368047</url>
      </button>
      <split/>
      If your acne is less severe, I can provide some advice. Are you interested?
      <think><set name="topic">ACNE</set></think>
      </template>
  </category>
  
  <topic name="ACNE">
      <category>
          <pattern>^ yes ^</pattern>
          <template> I have prepared 10 tips for you. Choose a number from 1-10 if you want only a single tip or type 'all' if you want to read all of them.</template>
      </category>
      <category>
          <pattern>*</pattern>
          <template>
              <think><set name="response"><star/></set></think>
              <condition name="response">
                  <li value="1">Avoid touching your face. This may cause flare-ups.</li>
                  <li value="2">Wash your face twice a day as usual but don't forget good moisturizing after that because water dries your skin. Dry skin produces more sebum and it causes more acne to develop.</li>
                  <li value="3">Be delicate with your skin. Use gentle, alcohol-free products. Don't use anything that may irritate your skin - if it stings, stop using it.</li>
                  <li value="4">Avoid exposing your skin to the sun for too long. Tanning damages you skin. What's more, some acne medications make the skin very sensitive to ultraviolet (UV) light, which you get from both the sun and indoor tanning devices.
You should always use sunscreen when staying under the sun, the higher the SPF (Sun Protection Factor) the better, but watch out for misleading advertising.</li>
                  <li value="5">Allow your skin to heal itself. If you pop your acne, your skin will take longer to clear and you increase the risk of getting acne scars. If you really need to, do it the right, least harmful way:
                  <button>
                      <text>How to pop a pimple</text>
                      <url>https://www.teenvogue.com/story/how-to-safely-pop-pimples</url>
                  </button>
                  </li>
                  <li value="6">Shampoo regularly. Oily hair can cause acne if it touches your face all the time. Hair products may not work properly  if they're not thoroughly washed off. Make sure to wash your hair properly and rinse away all the product that just may be clogging the pores near your hairline.</li>
                  <li value="7">Wash your pillowcases, hats and anything touching your skin for longer periods of time. They accumulate dead skin cells, bacteria and dirt, which can clog your pores.</li>
                  <li value="8">If your skin feels greasy, don't scrub it until it's clean. It can irritate your skin and make acne worse. Instead, use an enzymatic peeling which works well with your skin.</li>
                  <li value="9">Use a separate towel for your face and change it regularly. You can also use paper towels, which work even better, but are less environmentally-friendly.</li>
                  <li value="10">Too much stress and not enough sleep can both cause acne. Dermatologists advise to reduce stress and improve sleep hygiene, to let your body and skin to function properly. Stay healthy and allow yourself for some relaxation.</li>
                  <li value="all">
                        Avoid touching your face. This may couse flare-ups.
                          <delay>2</delay>
                        Wash your face twice a day as usual but don't forget good moisturizing after that because water dries your skin. Dry skin produces more sebum and it couses more acne to develop.
                          <delay>7</delay>
                          Be delicate with your skin. Use gentle, alcohol-free products. Don't use anything that may irritate your skin - if it stings, stop using it.
                          <delay>6</delay>
                          Avoid exposing your skin to the sun for too long. Tanning damages your skin. What's more, some acne medications make the skin very sensitive to ultraviolet (UV) light, which you get from both the sun and indoor tanning devices.
                          You should always use sunscreen when staying under the sun, the higher the SPF (Sun Protection Factor) the better, but watch out for misleading advertising.
                          <delay>17</delay>
                          Allow your skin to heal itself. If you pop your acne, your skin will take longer to clear and you increase the risk of getting acne scars. If you really need to, do it the right, least harmful way:
                             <button>
                               <text>How to pop a pimple</text>
                               <url>https://www.teenvogue.com/story/how-to-safely-pop-pimples</url>
                             </button> 
                          <delay>10</delay>
                          Shampoo regularly. Oily hair can cause acne if it touches your face all the time. Hair products may not work properly  if they're not thoroughly washed off. Make sure to wash your hair properly and rinse away all the product that just may be clogging the pores near your hairline.
                          <delay>9</delay>
                          Wash your pillowcases, hats and anything touching your skin for longer periods of time. They accumulate dead skin cells, bacteria and dirt, which can clog your pores.
                          <delay>7</delay>
                          If your skin feels greasy, don't scrub it until it's clean. It can irritate your skin and make acne worse. Instead, use an enzymatic peeling which works well with your skin.
                          <delay>7</delay>
                          Use a separate towel for your face and change it regularly. You can also use paper towels, which work even better, but are less environmentally-friendly.
                          <delay>7</delay>
                          Too much stress and not enough sleep can both cause acne. Dermatologists advise to reduce stress and improve sleep hygiene, to let your body and skin to function properly. Stay healthy and allow yourself for some relaxation.
                  </li>
                  <li>Do you want to:
                        <button>
                            <text>Test my Skin Type</text>
                            <postback>SkinType</postback>
                        </button>
                        <button>
                            <text>Tmprove my Skincare Routine</text>
                            <postback>Routine</postback>
                        </button>
                        <button>
                            <text>Ask a specific question</text>
                            <postback>Question</postback>
                        </button></li>
              </condition>
              </template>
      </category>
      
  </topic>
  
  <category>
      <pattern>^ wrinkles ^</pattern>
      <template>Wrinkles, also known as rhytides, are folds in your skin. As you age, your skin produces less of the proteins collagen and elastin. This makes your skin thinner and less resistant to damage.
     <button>
         <text>More information about Wrinkles you can find here</text>
         <url>https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/wrinkles/symptoms-causes/syc-20354927</url>
     </button>
     <split/>
     Want more?
      <set name="topic">WRINKLES</set>
      </template>
  </category>
  
  <topic name="WRINKLES">
      <category>
          <pattern>^ yes ^</pattern>
          <template>bla bla 10 tips </template>
      </category>
      <category>
          <pattern>*</pattern>
          <template><think><set name="response"><star/></set></think>
          <condition name="response">
              <li value="1">Wearing sunscreen with a sun protection factor (SPF) over 30 can not only help prevent skin cancer, but also helps delay the signs of aging. Wearing a moisturizing sunscreen on your face each day is a beneficial for your skin health long-term. </li>
              <li value="2">Sugar consumption can make you look older. Aging has also been linked to preparing food by grilling and frying, instead of baking or boiling. Limiting sugar and oil-rich foods in your diet will help you look younger for longer.</li>
              <li value="3">Smoking can age your face prematurely. Being around people smoking also can increase your risk for cancers and other diseases, and it may hurt your skin as well.</li>
              <li value="4">Coconut oil makes your skin feel smooth when applied directly. It also helps skin retain moisture, making your face appear fuller. Coconut oil has also been found to be an effective treatment for dry skin.</li>
              <li value="5">Beta carotenes block the sun’s ultraviolet light from damaging your skin and eyes. It is often an ingredient of anti-aging cosmetics, but it can also be taken as a supplement. As little as 30 milligrams per day of beta carotene, taken orally, can prevent and repair photoaging (otherwise known as wrinkles).</li>
              <li value="6">Lemon balm leaf extract makes skin more elastic and corrects tissue damage. It can be consumed in the form of lemon balm leaf tea.</li>
              <li value="7">Wrinkling on your face can be caused by the position that you sleep in. If your face is pressing against the pillow in the same way every night, over time, this compression leaves your skin weaker in some places than others, and a wrinkle forms. You can prevent or slow down compression wrinkles by sleeping on your back.</li>
              <li value="8">Wash your face before sleep, especially if you wear make-up. Avoid vigorously scrubbing your face. Use a water-based wipe to cleanse your face, and splash it with cold water when you're finished.</li>
              <li value="9">Ultraviolet light is the cause of most wrinkles on your face, neck, arms, and hands. Wear a hat that shields your face from the sun during long periods outdoors, and when possible, wear longer trousers and long-sleeved shirts. You’ll still absorb some sunshine, but you won’t be contributing to the wrinkles on your skin.</li>
              <li value="10">Antioxidants help fight the damage that oxidative stress does to your cells. Eating a diet rich in blueberries, kidney beans, grapes, kale, and spinach, along with using antioxidant-rich cosmetics, could reduce the signs of premature aging.</li>
              <li value="all">
                  Wearing sunscreen with a sun protection factor (SPF) over 30 can not only help prevent skin cancer, but also helps delay the signs of aging. Wearing a moisturizing sunscreen on your face each day is a beneficial for your skin health long-term.
                  <delay>10</delay>
                  Sugar consumption can make you look older. Aging has also been linked to preparing food by grilling and frying, instead of baking or boiling. Limiting sugar and oil-rich foods in your diet will help you look younger for longer.
                  <delay>10</delay>
                  Smoking can age your face prematurely. Being around people smoking also can increase your risk for cancers and other diseases, and it may hurt your skin as well.
                  <delay>7</delay>
                  Coconut oil makes your skin feel smooth when applied directly. It also helps skin retain moisture, making your face appear fuller. Coconut oil has also been found to be an effective treatment for dry skin.
                  <delay>10</delay>
                  Beta carotenes block the sun’s ultraviolet light from damaging your skin and eyes. It is often an ingredient of anti-aging cosmetics, but it can also be taken as a supplement. As little as 30 milligrams per day of beta carotene, taken orally, can prevent and repair photoaging (otherwise known as wrinkles).
                  <delay>15</delay>
                  Lemon balm leaf extract makes skin more elastic and corrects tissue damage. It can be consumed in the form of lemon balm leaf tea.
                  <delay>6</delay>
                  Wrinkling on your face can be caused by the position that you sleep in. If your face is pressing against the pillow in the same way every night, over time, this compression leaves your skin weaker in some places than others, and a wrinkle forms. You can prevent or slow down compression wrinkles by sleeping on your back.
                  <delay>15</delay>
                  Wash your face before sleep, especially if you wear make-up. Avoid vigorously scrubbing your face. Use a water-based wipe to cleanse your face, and splash it with cold water when you're finished.
                  <delay>10</delay>
                  Ultraviolet light is the cause of most wrinkles on your face, neck, arms, and hands. Wear a hat that shields your face from the sun during long periods outdoors, and when possible, wear longer trousers and long-sleeved shirts. You’ll still absorb some sunshine, but you won’t be contributing to the wrinkles on your skin.
                  <delay>15</delay>
                  Antioxidants help fight the damage that oxidative stress does to your cells. Eating a diet rich in blueberries, kidney beans, grapes, kale, and spinach, along with using antioxidant-rich cosmetics, could reduce the signs of premature aging.
              </li>
              <li>Do you want to:
                        <button>
                            <text>Test my Skin Type</text>
                            <postback>SkinType</postback>
                        </button>
                        <button>
                            <text>Tmprove my Skincare Routine</text>
                            <postback>Routine</postback>
                        </button>
                        <button>
                            <text>Ask a specific question</text>
                            <postback>Question</postback>
                        </button>
               </li>
          </condition>
          </template>
      </category>
  </topic>
 <!--Sources:
 1.https://www.healthline.com/health/beauty-skin-care/how-to-get-rid-of-wrinkles
 2.https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/wrinkles/symptoms-causes/syc-20354927
 3.https://www.byrdie.com/daily-skincare-routine#sensitive-skin
 4.https://www.almirall.com/your-health/your-skin/types-of-skin
 5.https://www.dermstore.com/blog/in-what-order-do-i-apply-my-skin-care-products-infographic/
 6.https://www.wikihow.com/Determine-Your-Skin-Type
 7.https://www.teenvogue.com/story/how-to-safely-pop-pimples
 8.https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/acne/symptoms-causes/syc-20368047
 9.https://www.webmd.com/beauty/whats-your-skin-type#1
 10.https://www.aad.org/public/diseases/acne/DIY/wont-clear
 11.https://www.aad.org/public/diseases/acne/skin-care/tips-->
</aiml>
